<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Brewe Academic</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Eric Brewe Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Eric Brewe Academic</title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Meetings With Students</title>
      <link>/post/individualmeetingswithstudents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/individualmeetingswithstudents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My class reached the halfway point this week. One of the things that I had planned was to have individual meetings with my students. This is a luxury of having a smaller class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I built a week into the course schedule where I didn&amp;rsquo;t add any new material. I had no idea about how quickly or slowly the couse was going to go at the beginning. So I added a week of flex at the half way point. It was there to allow me to catch up if I needed to, to give students a week to catch their breath, and to assess how they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was really smart&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my students are all physics majors, I found it weird that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t met many of them, and if they are going to be around for the next four years, I felt like I should have at least one conversation with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a bit about each of them, how they are handling quarantine, how they are adjusting to the pace and format of the class, and what they understood about the grades and grading system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things that I heard were that while the course was going ok, it also is a big difference for them. One student said, it is fine, but &amp;ldquo;I miss going to breakfast after class with the other students.&amp;rdquo; The need for connection was poigniant. A study of Drexel students revealed recently that students expect to pay substantially less for online classes. While this is problematic if you are a university administrator, the converse of this is that students value the interpersonal connection between student/faculty and student/student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things included that they weren&amp;rsquo;t looking at the gradebook (more on this later), and that they appreciated the opportunity to ask `little&amp;rsquo; questions (e.g. &amp;ldquo;How much explanation is enough?&amp;quot;, &amp;ldquo;How do I see the comments on the homework?&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I was able to encourage all of them to take the opportunity to resubmit homework for regrades. And as the week rolls on, I keep getting re-submissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus it was a week away from grading, a week where I could catch my breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on to the second half!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Plans</title>
      <link>/post/coursereplanningincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/coursereplanningincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, now I&amp;rsquo;ve done it. I have taught a week online. I had a day of logistics and getting to know (even though I don&amp;rsquo;t see people&amp;rsquo;s faces) the students on Monday. That did nothing to prepare me for the trainwreck that was going to be my first day of lecturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a ton about what I do when I lecture today.  My approach to lecture is the sort of standard &amp;ldquo;Chalk and Talk&amp;rdquo; sort of thing. I do not typically prepare a bunch of slides (or any actually). Typically I talk, write on the whiteboard and periodically pause to ask questions that I expect the students to answer verbally (e.g. &amp;ldquo;If the current here is 10, what would the current be over here?&amp;quot;). I also do not write out a script - I have an outline, and tend to work from the outline which allows me to improvise as I went along. So I assumed that is what I would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan has assumptions built into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed I would be able to use &amp;lt;Bitpaper.io&amp;gt; to make sketches and do the &amp;ldquo;Chalk&amp;rdquo; part, while I talked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed I would be able to ask questions of the students and get answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed my outline was about 50 minutes (gulp, not the case.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shit started unravelling for me beginning about 30 min before lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thirty min prior to lecture:&lt;/em&gt; Bitpaper only allows you one whiteboard / month for free, which I had not discovered because I only tried one at a time. So at the last minute I had to change to using Google&amp;rsquo;s Jamboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two min into lecture:&lt;/em&gt; I realized about 2 minutes in that my students all have their video off, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see their faces to see if they were understanding anything. They are also all muted so if I ask questions, they all answer using chat. This is ok, but I need to think through how to adapt my current style to this situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Five min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; My pen has this annoying feature, where it stopped working consistently and I had to keep switching back and forth between the pen and laser feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty five min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; I was both underprepared and overly optimistic. I need to have a much more detailed outline than I did today. I need to build in some time to have students have the opportunity to ask questions. I got through what I needed, but felt like I was both adding details that don&amp;rsquo;t need to be there and skipping over things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty six min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; I forgot to start recording the lecture. We are supposed to record all the synchronous class meetings, and I forgot, so my recording starts 26 min into class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fourty five min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; I use &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of gestures while I am teaching. This does not translate at all to the chalk and talk setup I have here. I truly don&amp;rsquo;t know what I can do about this, but be aware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty five min after lecture&lt;/em&gt; I have to do this again next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to do but get better, becasue that was about as bad as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Planning during Covid</title>
      <link>/post/courseplanningincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/courseplanningincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drexel is on the quarter system. And because students could not stay in dorms safely, Drexel announced that all classes during the spring quarter would be fully online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never taught a fully online course. I have never taught a course during a pandemic. I have never taught the course I was planning before (PHYS 115, Contemporary Physics III).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcment that all courses would be fully online was made right before final exams, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get to practice with one class online during Winter Term. I did get to practice with giving an online final exam through BlackBoard - but that is a different story.  What I did learn was that I did not want to give online exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class I am teaching is the third course in a three course sequence for physics majors. It uses Matter and Interactions, and I am in charge of content starting with magnetism. There are not quite 20 students in the class. It typically meets three times a week with a two hour long recitation/lab that has students engage in computational projects using vPython. I am teaching this class because the person that typically teaches it is on sabbatical, so there is an existing syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have the priveledge of having a stable family, good internet, a new computer, and two weeks of spring break (not spring break) to plan. So here is what I have come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-with-a-survey&#34;&gt;Starting with a survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had no idea what they wanted out of this, I decided to first survey the students. Where would they be (14/16 in Eastern Time Zone), what would their internet access be like (most fast, but not all), did they prefer graded or ungraded (pretty even split), synchronous/asynchronous/mixed (this was a mixed bag), and what are their concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-design&#34;&gt;Course Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Rachel Scherr said, &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t sign up for this. They did not sign up for this.&amp;rdquo; Everything is a set of decisions, and here are the decisions I decicded to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synchronousasynchronous&#34;&gt;Synchronous/Asynchronous?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The responses about this were pretty mixed, with some strongly requesting synchronous. My students will all be in North America, and the provost strongly suggested doing synchronous. So I decided a mix, with the week effectively starting on Wednesdays:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday - Synchronous - Introducing new material&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday - Asynchronous - Conceptual development activitie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday - Synchronous - Problem Solving workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;graded-or-passfail&#34;&gt;Graded or Pass/Fail?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students were pretty split on this, so I went with graded, based on the assessment system that I am working out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assessments&#34;&gt;Assessments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will set up a series of homework assignments (6-10 problems/week) that need to be written up with explanations. They will submit assignments each Monday, each problem will be graded with a rubric, and each week they can re-submit problems that they want to improve upon. The class is small, so I can do this - not sure how this scales to much larger classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational assignments, they will have four computational assignments.  They are going to do these in GlowScript, which is pretty similar to vPython and should run on everyone&amp;rsquo;s laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation, I am going to ask that people are engaged - by synchronously participating, by doing activities, or if they can not attend synchronously by watching the videos that we make in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check-ins. I think it is going to be important to check in with students about half way through the quarter, so I built in one week with just one:one meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finals. We are not going to have one. I see no reason to have one. I would rather have students do some sort of presentation (their favorite problem of the quarter?)  But we won&amp;rsquo;t have a final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, I need to have a set of tools that I am going to use and some that I have the students use. Here are the tools I am going with and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synchronous-meetings&#34;&gt;Synchronous Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have Zoom, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-whiteboard&#34;&gt;Virtual Whiteboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I present material, I want to be able to write on a whiteboard, so I have decided to use Bitpaper &amp;lt;bitpaper.io&amp;gt;, I can write on my Google Chromebook and have Zoom display what I am writing. Initially I thought students might work together on their own whiteboards, but I am concerned about requiring that.  I might try it depending on how things go.  I considered Google Jamboard, but like the display of bitpaper a bit better (particularly the eraser).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-computation&#34;&gt;Online Computation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class uses vPython. I do not. So evaluating tools such as trinket &lt;a href=&#34;https://trinket.io/&#34;&gt;https://trinket.io/&lt;/a&gt;, jupyter notebooks, google collaboratory, or GlowScript was a challenge. The first two use vPython from emacs (I say as if I know what I am talking about). But basically, the students all said GlowScript was the best option. The projects will have to be adapted, but hopefully I can have some serious help on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;classroom-communication&#34;&gt;Classroom Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have taught online before with classes that have a coding component, I found having a Slack for the classroom to be pretty useful.  Plus it lets them coordinate times to talk about howework etc.  They were into setting up a Discord server. But I am older so Slack it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;homework&#34;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned about Gradescope &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gradescope.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.gradescope.com/&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to give it a try anyway. But it seems to do all the things I want / need to be able to do and maybe will do it faster. Since we have a rubric that we will use for all assignments, it should be pretty useful. Plus it allows multiple resubmissions and re-grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these decisions out of the way I can actually start planning what we are going to do!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>/post/officehoursincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/officehoursincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a bad day on Wednesday, class was clunky, my technology kept freezing, and I felt bad about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today when 4 different students showed up for office hours I was a bit nervous.  It actually worked out much better than I had imagined.  First, each student was very understanding about the challenges, which I totally appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I found that I was able to manage the Zoom room, starting one breakout room so students could work on homework and jump back into the main room when they had questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to share my screen on my tablet and get bitpaper.io to work well and I even jumped to a PhET simulation at one point to talk through what they were trying to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the downside, I have wireless headphones which are great. But because they are wireless, you can leave and go to places like the bathroom with the headphones on.  Note to self, remember the mute button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I made what I think is a useful Zoom background.



  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/CoffeeBackground.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;/img/CoffeeBackground.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are small victories. But they are victories! Good to have a confidence boost going into next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
