<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Brewe Academic</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Eric Brewe Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Eric Brewe Academic</title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Planning during Covid</title>
      <link>/post/courseplanningincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/courseplanningincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drexel is on the quarter system. And because students could not stay in dorms safely, Drexel announced that all classes during the spring quarter would be fully online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never taught a fully online course. I have never taught a course during a pandemic. I have never taught the course I was planning before (PHYS 115, Contemporary Physics III).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcment that all courses would be fully online was made right before final exams, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get to practice with one class online during Winter Term. I did get to practice with giving an online final exam through BlackBoard - but that is a different story.  What I did learn was that I did not want to give online exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class I am teaching is the third course in a three course sequence for physics majors. It uses Matter and Interactions, and I am in charge of content starting with magnetism. There are not quite 20 students in the class. It typically meets three times a week with a two hour long recitation/lab that has students engage in computational projects using vPython. I am teaching this class because the person that typically teaches it is on sabbatical, so there is an existing syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have the priveledge of having a stable family, good internet, a new computer, and two weeks of spring break (not spring break) to plan. So here is what I have come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-with-a-survey&#34;&gt;Starting with a survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had no idea what they wanted out of this, I decided to first survey the students. Where would they be (14/16 in Eastern Time Zone), what would their internet access be like (most fast, but not all), did they prefer graded or ungraded (pretty even split), synchronous/asynchronous/mixed (this was a mixed bag), and what are their concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-design&#34;&gt;Course Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Rachel Scherr said, &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t sign up for this. They did not sign up for this.&amp;rdquo; Everything is a set of decisions, and here are the decisions I decicded to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synchronousasynchronous&#34;&gt;Synchronous/Asynchronous?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The responses about this were pretty mixed, with some strongly requesting synchronous. My students will all be in North America, and the provost strongly suggested doing synchronous. So I decided a mix, with the week effectively starting on Wednesdays:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday - Synchronous - Introducing new material&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday - Asynchronous - Conceptual development activitie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday - Synchronous - Problem Solving workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;graded-or-passfail&#34;&gt;Graded or Pass/Fail?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students were pretty split on this, so I went with graded, based on the assessment system that I am working out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assessments&#34;&gt;Assessments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will set up a series of homework assignments (6-10 problems/week) that need to be written up with explanations. They will submit assignments each Monday, each problem will be graded with a rubric, and each week they can re-submit problems that they want to improve upon. The class is small, so I can do this - not sure how this scales to much larger classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational assignments, they will have four computational assignments.  They are going to do these in GlowScript, which is pretty similar to vPython and should run on everyone&amp;rsquo;s laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation, I am going to ask that people are engaged - by synchronously participating, by doing activities, or if they can not attend synchronously by watching the videos that we make in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check-ins. I think it is going to be important to check in with students about half way through the quarter, so I built in one week with just one:one meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finals. We are not going to have one. I see no reason to have one. I would rather have students do some sort of presentation (their favorite problem of the quarter?)  But we won&amp;rsquo;t have a final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, I need to have a set of tools that I am going to use and some that I have the students use. Here are the tools I am going with and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synchronous-meetings&#34;&gt;Synchronous Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have Zoom, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-whiteboard&#34;&gt;Virtual Whiteboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I present material, I want to be able to write on a whiteboard, so I have decided to use Bitpaper &amp;lt;bitpaper.io&amp;gt;, I can write on my Google Chromebook and have Zoom display what I am writing. Initially I thought students might work together on their own whiteboards, but I am concerned about requiring that.  I might try it depending on how things go.  I considered Google Jamboard, but like the display of bitpaper a bit better (particularly the eraser).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-computation&#34;&gt;Online Computation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class uses vPython. I do not. So evaluating tools such as trinket &lt;a href=&#34;https://trinket.io/&#34;&gt;https://trinket.io/&lt;/a&gt;, jupyter notebooks, google collaboratory, or GlowScript was a challenge. The first two use vPython from emacs (I say as if I know what I am talking about). But basically, the students all said GlowScript was the best option. The projects will have to be adapted, but hopefully I can have some serious help on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;classroom-communication&#34;&gt;Classroom Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have taught online before with classes that have a coding component, I found having a Slack for the classroom to be pretty useful.  Plus it lets them coordinate times to talk about howework etc.  They were into setting up a Discord server. But I am older so Slack it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;homework&#34;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned about Gradescope &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gradescope.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.gradescope.com/&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to give it a try anyway. But it seems to do all the things I want / need to be able to do and maybe will do it faster. Since we have a rubric that we will use for all assignments, it should be pretty useful. Plus it allows multiple resubmissions and re-grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these decisions out of the way I can actually start planning what we are going to do!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
