<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Eric Brewe Academic</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving Workshops at a distance</title>
      <link>/post/problem-solving-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/problem-solving-workshops/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;My teaching agenda includes weekly problem solving workshops. The idea is that students should have time to work together on solving some problems. It has taken three different flavors thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students have a question about the homework problem that is due on Mondays. If someone asks, we will work on the problem in small groups and then come back together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students all work on a problem that illustrates something that I want to emphasize. This is good practice when I want students to have a common starting point for more complex problems or when I want to emphasize different approaches to solving a single problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students are in groups and each group is assigned a different problem. This works well when they are not struggling with the problems, and I want them to have the opportunity to see lots of different problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how to make this work at a distance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamboard.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Jamboard&lt;/a&gt;, because I can set up a separate board for each group before class, with a unique url. In the jamboard, I include the problem that I want them to work on, either as a link, or a picture, or today I used a sticky note. One of the things that I have to remember is to set the sharing options so that anyone with the link can edit (otherwise no one can write on the jamboard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I have set up the jamboards, I find it important to keep a google doc that has the links for each group and the group number, so I can quickly share these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Zoom, I have people join breakout rooms (3-4 per room). Then I cycle through the rooms and using the chat function assign each room a problem (that is why having the links handy is useful).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I managed to put all four jamboards on my extra monitor, so I could keep track of how groups were making progress. It was so cool!🎉👏👍 I felt like I was in some sort of problem solving command center. I was able to see groups making progress, I didn’t have to move from Zoom breakout rooms to pose questions (in one group I asked a question by adding a sticky note), and then I noticed another group didn’t seem to be making much progress so I joined that breakout room and was able to help out a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love having students work problems out together because I think it does a ton of good. This isn’t quite that, but I’ll take small victories💥!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards Based Grading</title>
      <link>/post/standards-based-grading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/standards-based-grading/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;My plan for this course has been to use standards based grading on weekly assignments. The basic theory of this practice is that we should be assessing students on their understanding, so this means that they have to demonstrate said understanding. They do this in my class by submitting weekly homework (not a big deal). The big difference in standards-based grading is that each problem is evaluated on a standardized rubric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need a rubric. But I also know that websites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chegg.com/&#34;&gt;Chegg&lt;/a&gt; make it super easy to find answers to textbook problems. So a rubric that just evaluates answers may not ensure that students are demonstrating understanding. The rubric I have developed then focuses on explanation of their solutions. It is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width=&#34;30%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;col width=&#34;69%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Score&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fully complete, well explained, all work shown, correct answer someone could pick up this solution and read it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Complete, explained adquately, work shown, correct answer. Someone would probably understand this solution.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Missing either adequate explanation or work, answer is correct, but someone would struggle to understand what you’ve done to get to this solution.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Missing either adequate explanation or work and answer is incorrect.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No or very little effort demonstrated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the students’ grades are determined based on the proportion of the problems that are evaluated as satisfactory. So for example, if a student submits 100% of the problems, but only 85% are evaluated as satisfactory, then that student would have an 85%. Another student who submits only 80% of the problems but every problem submitted is evaluated as satisfactory would get an 80%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This grading scheme is interesting becasue it is not what physics majors have typically experienced. They are used to solving problems and focusing on right answers. It is possible for a student to have correctly solved every problem, but have not explained anything (meaning no words), and that student will have a 0%! One of the biggest challenges I have is helping students to break this habit of submitting solutions without any explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is not the end though. Because the goal is for students to achieve standards, I also allow for students to resubmit work (up to 9 times). This helps to alleviate the issue of students who have solved problems correctly, but haven’t explained. Go back, explain, and resubmit. You can take a 0% to a 100% fairly efficiently. Hopefully, it encourages students to review their feedback and consider the work they have submitted - at least that is the ideal. Currently, it feels like about 1/3 of the class is fully on board - including explanations and writing up work thoroughly and many times beautifully. One third has not used a single word in any of their problems - so we talked aobut this in class today. And the middle third hasn’t quite calibrated their explanations, sometimes they are doing it effectively and sometimes not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process is interesting, I am testing it at a small scale (16 students). I am evaluating relatively harshly in the beginning as I find that if I don’t they won’t come to the realization that they need to incorporate explanations. Gradescope makes this process pretty easy as I built the rubric one time and use it over and over for each problem. But that is a different post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards Based Grading With Gradescope and R</title>
      <link>/post/standards-based-grading-gradescope-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/standards-based-grading-gradescope-and-r/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Initially, I wrote this post first, but then realized that I needed to talk about Standards Based Grading before I launched into the weird realities I discovered trying to implement SBG. So I wrote about SBG in a separate post &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericbrewe.com/post/standards-based-grading/&#34;&gt;Standards Based Grading&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory is good, but implementing it means I need to be able to accomplish a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need a gradebook that calculates the proportion of problems that are satisfactory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need a gradebook that students can check online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to be able to revise these grades as students resubmit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to be able to accept resubmissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, and foremost, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gradescope.com/&#34;&gt;Gradescope&lt;/a&gt; is pretty well set up to collect electronic homework and to allow you to grade homework electronically. For this part, you write up a homework pdf, create a homework assignment, select your grading preferences (I choose positive scoring, with 0-4 as the possible score for each problem), set some due dates, and add a rubric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote one rubric, that I apply to each problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width=&#34;30%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;col width=&#34;69%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Score&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fully complete, well explained, all work shown, correct answer someone could pick up this solution and read it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Complete, explained adquately, work shown, correct answer. Someone would probably understand this solution.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Missing either adequate explanation or work, answer is correct, but someone would struggle to understand what you’ve done to get to this solution.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Missing either adequate explanation or work and answer is incorrect.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No or very little effort demonstrated&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grading on Gradescope is somewhat faster than by hand, as I can read a problem solution and just push a button and it will assign that score. You can also annotate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So collecting homework isn’t a problem. The problem arose when I needed to be able to collect resubmissions. This isn’t built easily into Gradescope, though when I emailed them they came back with four suggestions quickly, Nice Work Olga! To handle resubmissions, I set each homework to allow for late submissions and set the due date on late submissions to the end of the grading period. That way students can upload as many times as they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I graded my first assignment, and then realized that BlackBoard (our content management system) and Gradescope don’t easily allow you to maintain a gradebook that looks at proportion of problems above a certain score. I know R, why not just build my own gradebook. So that is what I have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gradescope allows you to download a csv file that includes a Student ID, their scores on individual problems and their email. There is a bunch we can work with. But there is a problem, I can’t post grades based on any of those things, and BlackBoard does not do grades based on a proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I assigned each student a randomly generated number and added it to the gradebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ID_Postable = sample(1000:9999, nrow(gradebook), replace = F)

gradebook %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(ID_Post = ID_Postable) -&amp;gt; gradebook
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a problem. Grading systems all calculate based on percent scores so a student with all 2s would get a 50%. I need a grading system. I have a gradebook, but need to calculate the proportion of problem scores that are evaluated as satisfactory. The work flow is Pull in weekly grades, clean up the column names, calculate a weekly proportion of satisfactory problems, then add this to the total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I wrote a function to clean up the names of the weekly grades and to limit what we included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;CleanAndNameFunction = function(df,Ch){
  df &amp;lt;- df %&amp;gt;%
    select(-c(Name, Email, `Total Score`, Status, `Submission ID`, `Submission Time`, `Lateness (H:M:S)`, `View Count`) )
  
  df %&amp;gt;% 
    select(-SID) %&amp;gt;%
    names(.) %&amp;gt;%
    str_extract_all(&amp;quot;: [PQ0-9]+&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
    str_extract_all(&amp;quot;[PQ0-9]+&amp;quot;) -&amp;gt; ProbNames
  
  ProbNames = unlist(ProbNames)
  #Assign names of Problems
  names(df)[2:length(df)] = ProbNames
  
  #Adds the Chapter Number to each of the problem column names
  df &amp;lt;- df %&amp;gt;%
    rename_at(vars(ProbNames), function(x) paste0(&amp;quot;Ch&amp;quot;, Chapter, x))
  
  df
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have to calculate the proportion of the problems in any given week that are satisfactory (in my case, this means a score above 2). R and the Tidyverse are good, but really focus on analysis by columns, doing this was surprisingly more difficult than I had thought. So I wrote a function that identifies all the data, then it evaluates each column as to whether it is above the cutoff score, but that evaluates to TRUE/FALSE, so that has to be converted to numeric and rowSums (the dplyr version) was calculated. Then I renamed to ChapterNGood (the number that are satisfactory), ChapterNPoss (the number of problems), and the ChapterGoodPercent (satisfactory / possible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;PercentAbove = function(df, Ch){
  Chap = paste0(&amp;quot;Ch&amp;quot;,Ch)
  
  df %&amp;gt;%
    select(starts_with(Chap)) %&amp;gt;%
    mutate_all(function(x) as.numeric(x&amp;gt;2)) %&amp;gt;%
    mutate(NGood = rowSums(.)) %&amp;gt;%
    mutate(PercentGood = 100*NGood/(length(.)-1)) %&amp;gt;%
    mutate(Poss = length(.)-2) %&amp;gt;%
    select(NGood, Poss, PercentGood) %&amp;gt;%
    rename_at(vars(NGood, Poss, PercentGood), function(x) paste0(Chap, x)) %&amp;gt;%
    bind_cols(df) %&amp;gt;%
    select(SID,everything())
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooray! But now we need to blend these data back into the gradebook and calculate the overall proportion of scores that are satisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t yet have this as a function, because it will certainly use a quosure…but this does it for two chapters…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;OverallScores &amp;lt;- gradebook %&amp;gt;%
  select(SID, ID_Post, contains(&amp;quot;Poss&amp;quot;), contains(&amp;quot;Good&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;%
  select(SID, ID_Post, contains(&amp;quot;Ch18&amp;quot;), contains(&amp;quot;Ch19&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(OverallPercent = (Ch18PercentGood*Ch18Poss + Ch19PercentGood*Ch19Poss)/(Ch18Poss + Ch19Poss))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! It works. Now I just need to figure out how to post these so they can be published anonymously and accessible electronically. This means Shiny 😬! But perhaps that is a separate post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental Improvements</title>
      <link>/post/improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/improvements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After last week&amp;rsquo;s trainwreck of a class I knew I had to make some changes. So this week I wrote 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ericbrewe.com/slides/chslides/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a ton of slides.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus side, they look great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minus side, I made something like 9 million git commits and it took me forever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as a result, class today went much more smoothly. There were a few differences from last week that I noticed. First, the students during office hours said that they were going to start turning their cameras on so I could see peoples&amp;rsquo; faces and responses.  That was a big difference. Second, there was a ton more new material this week, so having the slides allowed me to go through it efficiently. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get as far as I might have liked, but that is ok. We&amp;rsquo;ll do clean up work on Monday during the problem solving bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned a ton about how to get these slides made and will use this going forward.  I don&amp;rsquo;t think getting slides like this is totally critical, and I suppose the outcome of this post is that if you make slides, you can go fast (which sucks).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Plans</title>
      <link>/post/coursereplanningincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/coursereplanningincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, now I&amp;rsquo;ve done it. I have taught a week online. I had a day of logistics and getting to know (even though I don&amp;rsquo;t see people&amp;rsquo;s faces) the students on Monday. That did nothing to prepare me for the trainwreck that was going to be my first day of lecturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a ton about what I do when I lecture today.  My approach to lecture is the sort of standard &amp;ldquo;Chalk and Talk&amp;rdquo; sort of thing. I do not typically prepare a bunch of slides (or any actually). Typically I talk, write on the whiteboard and periodically pause to ask questions that I expect the students to answer verbally (e.g. &amp;ldquo;If the current here is 10, what would the current be over here?&amp;quot;). I also do not write out a script - I have an outline, and tend to work from the outline which allows me to improvise as I went along. So I assumed that is what I would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan has assumptions built into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed I would be able to use &amp;lt;Bitpaper.io&amp;gt; to make sketches and do the &amp;ldquo;Chalk&amp;rdquo; part, while I talked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed I would be able to ask questions of the students and get answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assumed my outline was about 50 minutes (gulp, not the case.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shit started unravelling for me beginning about 30 min before lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thirty min prior to lecture:&lt;/em&gt; Bitpaper only allows you one whiteboard / month for free, which I had not discovered because I only tried one at a time. So at the last minute I had to change to using Google&amp;rsquo;s Jamboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two min into lecture:&lt;/em&gt; I realized about 2 minutes in that my students all have their video off, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see their faces to see if they were understanding anything. They are also all muted so if I ask questions, they all answer using chat. This is ok, but I need to think through how to adapt my current style to this situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Five min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; My pen has this annoying feature, where it stopped working consistently and I had to keep switching back and forth between the pen and laser feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty five min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; I was both underprepared and overly optimistic. I need to have a much more detailed outline than I did today. I need to build in some time to have students have the opportunity to ask questions. I got through what I needed, but felt like I was both adding details that don&amp;rsquo;t need to be there and skipping over things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty six min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; I forgot to start recording the lecture. We are supposed to record all the synchronous class meetings, and I forgot, so my recording starts 26 min into class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fourty five min into lecture&lt;/em&gt; I use &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of gestures while I am teaching. This does not translate at all to the chalk and talk setup I have here. I truly don&amp;rsquo;t know what I can do about this, but be aware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twenty five min after lecture&lt;/em&gt; I have to do this again next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing to do but get better, becasue that was about as bad as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Planning during Covid</title>
      <link>/post/courseplanningincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/courseplanningincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drexel is on the quarter system. And because students could not stay in dorms safely, Drexel announced that all classes during the spring quarter would be fully online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never taught a fully online course. I have never taught a course during a pandemic. I have never taught the course I was planning before (PHYS 115, Contemporary Physics III).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The announcment that all courses would be fully online was made right before final exams, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get to practice with one class online during Winter Term. I did get to practice with giving an online final exam through BlackBoard - but that is a different story.  What I did learn was that I did not want to give online exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The class I am teaching is the third course in a three course sequence for physics majors. It uses Matter and Interactions, and I am in charge of content starting with magnetism. There are not quite 20 students in the class. It typically meets three times a week with a two hour long recitation/lab that has students engage in computational projects using vPython. I am teaching this class because the person that typically teaches it is on sabbatical, so there is an existing syllabus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have the priveledge of having a stable family, good internet, a new computer, and two weeks of spring break (not spring break) to plan. So here is what I have come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-with-a-survey&#34;&gt;Starting with a survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had no idea what they wanted out of this, I decided to first survey the students. Where would they be (14/16 in Eastern Time Zone), what would their internet access be like (most fast, but not all), did they prefer graded or ungraded (pretty even split), synchronous/asynchronous/mixed (this was a mixed bag), and what are their concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-design&#34;&gt;Course Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Rachel Scherr said, &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t sign up for this. They did not sign up for this.&amp;rdquo; Everything is a set of decisions, and here are the decisions I decicded to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synchronousasynchronous&#34;&gt;Synchronous/Asynchronous?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The responses about this were pretty mixed, with some strongly requesting synchronous. My students will all be in North America, and the provost strongly suggested doing synchronous. So I decided a mix, with the week effectively starting on Wednesdays:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday - Synchronous - Introducing new material&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday - Asynchronous - Conceptual development activitie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday - Synchronous - Problem Solving workshop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;graded-or-passfail&#34;&gt;Graded or Pass/Fail?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students were pretty split on this, so I went with graded, based on the assessment system that I am working out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;assessments&#34;&gt;Assessments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will set up a series of homework assignments (6-10 problems/week) that need to be written up with explanations. They will submit assignments each Monday, each problem will be graded with a rubric, and each week they can re-submit problems that they want to improve upon. The class is small, so I can do this - not sure how this scales to much larger classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational assignments, they will have four computational assignments.  They are going to do these in GlowScript, which is pretty similar to vPython and should run on everyone&amp;rsquo;s laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation, I am going to ask that people are engaged - by synchronously participating, by doing activities, or if they can not attend synchronously by watching the videos that we make in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check-ins. I think it is going to be important to check in with students about half way through the quarter, so I built in one week with just one:one meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finals. We are not going to have one. I see no reason to have one. I would rather have students do some sort of presentation (their favorite problem of the quarter?)  But we won&amp;rsquo;t have a final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this, I need to have a set of tools that I am going to use and some that I have the students use. Here are the tools I am going with and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synchronous-meetings&#34;&gt;Synchronous Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have Zoom, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;virtual-whiteboard&#34;&gt;Virtual Whiteboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I present material, I want to be able to write on a whiteboard, so I have decided to use Bitpaper &amp;lt;bitpaper.io&amp;gt;, I can write on my Google Chromebook and have Zoom display what I am writing. Initially I thought students might work together on their own whiteboards, but I am concerned about requiring that.  I might try it depending on how things go.  I considered Google Jamboard, but like the display of bitpaper a bit better (particularly the eraser).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-computation&#34;&gt;Online Computation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This class uses vPython. I do not. So evaluating tools such as trinket &lt;a href=&#34;https://trinket.io/&#34;&gt;https://trinket.io/&lt;/a&gt;, jupyter notebooks, google collaboratory, or GlowScript was a challenge. The first two use vPython from emacs (I say as if I know what I am talking about). But basically, the students all said GlowScript was the best option. The projects will have to be adapted, but hopefully I can have some serious help on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;classroom-communication&#34;&gt;Classroom Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have taught online before with classes that have a coding component, I found having a Slack for the classroom to be pretty useful.  Plus it lets them coordinate times to talk about howework etc.  They were into setting up a Discord server. But I am older so Slack it will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;homework&#34;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned about Gradescope &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gradescope.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.gradescope.com/&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to give it a try anyway. But it seems to do all the things I want / need to be able to do and maybe will do it faster. Since we have a rubric that we will use for all assignments, it should be pretty useful. Plus it allows multiple resubmissions and re-grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these decisions out of the way I can actually start planning what we are going to do!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>/post/officehoursincrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/officehoursincrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a bad day on Wednesday, class was clunky, my technology kept freezing, and I felt bad about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today when 4 different students showed up for office hours I was a bit nervous.  It actually worked out much better than I had imagined.  First, each student was very understanding about the challenges, which I totally appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I found that I was able to manage the Zoom room, starting one breakout room so students could work on homework and jump back into the main room when they had questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to share my screen on my tablet and get bitpaper.io to work well and I even jumped to a PhET simulation at one point to talk through what they were trying to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the downside, I have wireless headphones which are great. But because they are wireless, you can leave and go to places like the bathroom with the headphones on.  Note to self, remember the mute button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I made what I think is a useful Zoom background.



  











&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/CoffeeBackground.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;/img/CoffeeBackground.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are small victories. But they are victories! Good to have a confidence boost going into next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
